<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Special commands on standardese</title>
    <link>https://standardese.github.io/020_overview/commands/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Special commands on standardese</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 10:35:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://standardese.github.io/020_overview/commands/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Command</title>
      <link>https://standardese.github.io/020_overview/commands/010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:27:37 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standardese.github.io/020_overview/commands/010/</guid>
      <description>A command is used to control the documentation generation in some way. A text that begins with a command doesn&amp;rsquo;t appear in the output documentation at all.
There are the following commands:
 verbatim - This command isn&amp;rsquo;t like the other commands. It can happen anywhere in a line — i.e. where CommonMark allows an inline entity like emphasis. The text following the command until an end command or the end of the line will be inserted as-is into the output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Section</title>
      <link>https://standardese.github.io/020_overview/commands/011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:27:37 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standardese.github.io/020_overview/commands/011/</guid>
      <description>A section is the basic way of standardese documentation. It supports all the sections the C++ standard uses, as explained in the example. Those sections will create a paragraph in the output prefixed with a human readable name. There are two special sections, brief and details. They are not labeled in the output.
Unlike for a command text following a section is included in the output. A section is active for the rest of the paragraph, a hard line break or until another special command is encountered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inline</title>
      <link>https://standardese.github.io/020_overview/commands/020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:27:37 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standardese.github.io/020_overview/commands/020/</guid>
      <description>A inline is a special kind of command. They are param, tparam and base and used to document (template) parameters and base classes, because you cannot put a corresponding comment there. As such they are shorthands for the \entity unique-name command. They are followed by the name of entity they refer to.
The inline and argument is stripped from the text. The rest of the line will be treated as brief documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>