<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>STANDARDESE on standardese</title>
    <link>https://standardese.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in STANDARDESE on standardese</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://standardese.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Example</title>
      <link>https://standardese.github.io/010_start/010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:27:37 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standardese.github.io/010_start/010/</guid>
      <description>Consider the following C++ header file named swap.hpp:
#include &amp;lt;type_traits&amp;gt; namespace std { /// \effects Exchanges values stored in two locations. /// \requires Type `T` shall be `MoveConstructible` and `MoveAssignable`. template &amp;lt;class T&amp;gt; void swap(T &amp;amp;a, T &amp;amp;b) noexcept(is_nothrow_move_constructible&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;::value &amp;amp;&amp;amp; is_nothrow_move_assignable&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;::value); }  This will generate the following documentation:
#Header file swap.hpp
#include &amp;lt;type_traits&amp;gt; namespace std { template &amp;lt;typename T&amp;gt; void swap(T &amp;amp; a, T &amp;amp; b) noexcept(is_nothrow_move_constructible&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;::value &amp;amp;&amp;amp; is_nothrow_move_assignable&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;::value); }  ##Function template swap&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Command</title>
      <link>https://standardese.github.io/020_overview/commands/010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:27:37 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standardese.github.io/020_overview/commands/010/</guid>
      <description>A command is used to control the documentation generation in some way. A text that begins with a command doesn&amp;rsquo;t appear in the output documentation at all.
There are the following commands:
 verbatim - This command isn&amp;rsquo;t like the other commands. It can happen anywhere in a line — i.e. where CommonMark allows an inline entity like emphasis. The text following the command until an end command or the end of the line will be inserted as-is into the output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syntax</title>
      <link>https://standardese.github.io/020_overview/010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:27:37 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standardese.github.io/020_overview/010/</guid>
      <description>standardese looks for documentation comments as shown in the following example:
/// A regular C++ style documentation comment. /// Multiple C++ style comments are merged automatically. /// This line has *two* leading whitespaces because one is always skipped. //! A C++ style comment using an exclamation mark. /// It will also merge with other C++ style comments. //! But don&#39;t worry, also with the exclamation mark styles. /** A C style documentation commment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installation</title>
      <link>https://standardese.github.io/010_start/011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:27:37 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standardese.github.io/010_start/011/</guid>
      <description>Very Easy: Pre-compiled Binaries TODO
Easy: Docker The easiest way to build standardese is to download the docker image foonathan/standardese_dev and run it like so:
docker pull foonathan/standardese_dev docker run -v &amp;quot;/path/to/standardese/source:/root/standardese&amp;quot; -v &amp;quot;$(pwd):/root/output&amp;quot; foonathan/standardese_dev  It will compile standardese as a fully statically linked binary and copy it to the current working directory. The binary is compatible with any Linux distribution.
Harder: Building From Source The build system takes care of all dependencies automatically, except for two: Boost and libclang.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linking</title>
      <link>https://standardese.github.io/020_overview/011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:27:37 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standardese.github.io/020_overview/011/</guid>
      <description>To link to an entity, use the syntax [link-text](&amp;lt;&amp;gt; &amp;quot;unique-name&amp;quot;) (a CommonMark link with empty URL and a title of unique-name). If you don&amp;rsquo;t want a special link-text, this can be shortened to [unique-name]() (a CommonMark link with empty URL and the name of an entity as text). You can also use an URL of the following form [link-text](standardese://unique-name/ &amp;quot;optional-title&amp;quot;) (a normal CommonMark link with the standardese:// protocol, the &amp;lsquo;/&amp;rsquo; at the end is important).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Section</title>
      <link>https://standardese.github.io/020_overview/commands/011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:27:37 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standardese.github.io/020_overview/commands/011/</guid>
      <description>A section is the basic way of standardese documentation. It supports all the sections the C++ standard uses, as explained in the example. Those sections will create a paragraph in the output prefixed with a human readable name. There are two special sections, brief and details. They are not labeled in the output.
Unlike for a command text following a section is included in the output. A section is active for the rest of the paragraph, a hard line break or until another special command is encountered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Command line</title>
      <link>https://standardese.github.io/010_start/020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:27:37 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standardese.github.io/010_start/020/</guid>
      <description>The tool uses Boost.ProgramOptions for the options parsing, --help gives a good overview.
Basic usage is: standardese [options] inputs
The inputs can be both files or directories, in case of directory each file is documented, unless an input option is specified (see below). The tool will currently generate a corresponding Markdown file with the documentation for each file it gets as input. Files that are not source files (determined by the input.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>External Links</title>
      <link>https://standardese.github.io/020_overview/020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:27:37 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standardese.github.io/020_overview/020/</guid>
      <description>You can also link to external documentations via the tool option --comment.external_doc prefix=url. All unique-names starting with prefix will be linked to the url. If the url contains two dollar signs $$, they will be replaced by the unique-name. By default the tool supports http://en.cppreference.com/w/ with a prefix of std:: by default.
 You can override to a different URL by specifying --comment.external_doc std::=new-url.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inline</title>
      <link>https://standardese.github.io/020_overview/commands/020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:27:37 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standardese.github.io/020_overview/commands/020/</guid>
      <description>A inline is a special kind of command. They are param, tparam and base and used to document (template) parameters and base classes, because you cannot put a corresponding comment there. As such they are shorthands for the \entity unique-name command. They are followed by the name of entity they refer to.
The inline and argument is stripped from the text. The rest of the line will be treated as brief documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Name lookup</title>
      <link>https://standardese.github.io/020_overview/025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:27:37 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standardese.github.io/020_overview/025/</guid>
      <description>If you prefix a unique name with * or ?, this will do a name lookup, looking for the entity. This only works inside a comment associated with an entity, not in template files etc.
It does a similar search to the actual name lookup in C++: It starts at the associated entity and appends its scope to the partial unique name given, going to the next higher entity if no matching entity can be found, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CMake</title>
      <link>https://standardese.github.io/010_start/030/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:27:37 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standardese.github.io/010_start/030/</guid>
      <description>To ease the compilation options, you can call standardese from CMake like so:
find_package(standardese REQUIRED) # find standardese after installation # generates a custom target that will run standardese to generate the documentation standardese_generate(my_target CONFIG path/to/config_file INCLUDE_DIRECTORY ${my_target_includedirs} INPUT ${headers})  It will use a custom target that runs standardese. You can specify the compilation options and inputs directly in CMake to allow shared variables. All other options must be given in a config file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Template syntax</title>
      <link>https://standardese.github.io/020_overview/040/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:27:37 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standardese.github.io/020_overview/040/</guid>
      <description>Note: Not implemented on develop at the moment.
 If you pass a file that is not a source file, it will be treated as template file and processed. This allows advanced control over the output or writing additional documentation files.
standardese will read the file and replace two things:
 URLs with the standardese:// protocol will be converted to the correct URL for the given entity. This allows referring to documentation entities from other files without manually having to deal with the URLs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acknowledgements</title>
      <link>https://standardese.github.io/thanks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standardese.github.io/thanks/</guid>
      <description>Manu @Manu343726 Sánchez, as always
 Jason @jpleau Pleau, for much feedback and requests on Gitter
 Mark @DarkerStar Gibbs, for feature suggestions
 Tristan @tcbrindle Brindle, for (better) clang support
 Marek @mkurdej Kurdej, for (better) MSVC support
 Victor @vitaut Zverovich, for bugfixes
 John @johnmcfarlane McFarlane, for issue reporting
 Filipe @verri Verri, for maintaining the AUR package
 @topisani, for issue reporting and bugfixes
 Trim @bresilla Bresilla, for our logo</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>